so how do we implement reusable barriers
correctly this is how the idea here is
that the value for releasing the barrier
will not be the same for all instances
of the barrier even instances when
release becomes zero all the instances
are gonna release when release becomes
one so the idea is that we never really
need to reinitialize the release we just
flip the release each thread now has a
local sense which is kind of what's the
release that we should get in order to
get out so if we have two threads 0 and
1 let's say that they started with local
sense being 0 now they're gonna get here
and they're both gonna figure out that
the local sense is 1 local sense is
local to each thread so each of them
just sets a local variable independently
so this is not going to interfere with
each other now one of the thread will
enter the counter LOC increment the
count and here if the count is equal to
the total they will reset the count and
set the release to local sense so it
sets the release to what we are waiting
for in this case let's say thread 1
releases it to 1 that means that thread
0 when it incremented account didn't see
the total add to it so it at 1 and
proceeded to exit here and enters this
weight here it's waiting now for the
release to become what it thinks local
senses which is 1 so it's going to spin
until somebody puts one into the release
eventually thread 1 does that so now
let's say that thread 0 is stuck here
that was the problem with the previous
implementation of the barrier let's say
that we just don't read it fast enough
so we want to see a 1 but we don't check
it fast enough thread 1 now proceeds to
exit finishes the work and comes back to
the second instance of the barrier it
now flips its own local sense to 0
increments the count to 1 because we
reset the count when we were releasing
the first instance checks the count sees
that it is 1 doesn't do this unlocks the
lock
and enters the spin here but thread one
is now checking whether the release has
become zero because it flipped the local
sense now it's waiting for this value
for the release so they're waiting for
different value
note that the release is still the same
as thread one left it in the first
instance
so eventually thread zero will check and
see that the release has become one at
which point it will leave eventually
it's gonna come here change its local
sense to zero increment the count see
that it's to reset the count set the
release to zero this time and now thread
one will be released so by flipping the
value of the release instead of
reinitializing it in each iteration of
the loop we avoid the problem that we
had so this barrier is reusable we can
synchronize on the same barrier over and
over without risking deadlock situations